# Ayush Sharma

#### Contact

### Phone:

+1 (678)-330-0438

### **Emails:**

ayushs217@gmail.com asharma628@gatech.edu asharma36@student.gsu.edu

### Languages

English

Hindi

Latin



### **Profile**

Freshman Undergraduate Computer Science major from Georgia State University (3.83 GPA) with experience in various fields of technology and engineering such as iOS & Android app development, Amazon Web Services (AWS), HTML/CSS, Java, and Python

I have had the pleasure to work for technology conglomerates, universities and 501c(3) non-profit organizations such as Lockheed Martin, Microsoft, Georgia Institute of Technology, North American Thrombosis Forum, International Rescue Committee, Pennies for Patients and the Red Cross.

Industrious, diligent and fast learning student with 4+ years of experience in a technology real-world environment.

### **Work Experience**

09/2019 - Present

### **STEM Mentor – Georgia Institute of Technology**

- Employed at CEISMC (Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics and Computing) at Georgia Institute of Technology
- Teach High School Juniors about STEM at the Davis Charter Senior Academy
- Worked with Horizons and K.I.D.S/STEAM program at Georgia Institute of Technology
- Teaching elementary and middle school kids about the wonders of STEM

05/2019 - Present

# Co-Founder, Chief Executive Officer – 4 Years

Primary Responsibilities:

- Lead developer of 4 Years website and Accepted Student Database
- Partnered with Microsoft to sponsor a college exposition panel event on November 27th, 2019.
- Manages ACT tutoring team of 35 and website development team of 5
- Collaborates with 4 Years executive team to find new innovative strategies to help elevate the user experience and create new streams of revenue

11/2018 - 03/2019

# Lead Front-End Website Developer – International Rescue Committee

Responsibilities:

- Collaborated with a team of 15 website developers and help create website for Food for ATL
- Worked with International Rescue Committee to spearhead the effort of developing a software system that helps deliver food to refugees
- Lead a team of 3 front-end website developers and developed the UI for the Food For ATL website - An International Rescue Committee subsidiary

### **Student Representative – Microsoft**

Responsibilities:

- Organized a technology event with Microsoft in April of 2019
- Lead National Technical Honor Society officer team of 8 to manage 120 volunteers and 300 participants
- Collaborated with Microsoft employees at the Linux and Perimeter mall retail store to set up the technology fair event at the Microsoft Avalon corporate office

05/2018 - 07/2018

# **Engineer Intern – Lockheed Martin**

Responsibilities:

- Worked with Lockheed Martin & Aerospace Systems Design Laboratory (ASDL) at Georgia Institute of Technology
- Developed a quad copter with a team of 3 that was used as an Air Package Delivery System (APDS) embedded with Artificial Intelligence capabilities
  - Had the ability to go around object
  - Adjust flight ceiling depending on the height of the obstacle
  - Ability to land at a designated location without manual control
  - Can scan obstacles nearby and identify height, span and width of the obstacle

03/2016 - 10/2018

# Article Writer - Georgia Thrombosis Forum

Responsibilities:

- Volunteer Group Leader for 3 booths (TAMA, Suwannee Festival, Run for SEVA)
- Published an interview with a patient diagnosed with DVT in the North American Thrombosis Forum paper.
- Published an article with a colleague in North Fulton
  Newspaper "The Paper" titled: Thrombosis is the silent killer.
- Conducted an international survey about the awareness levels of thrombosis in Mumbai. Published a scientific article about findings of the study in the North American Thrombosis Forum

### **Education**

High School Diploma, Alpharetta High School

2015 - 2019

2019 - 2023

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Georgia State University

### Skills

Soft Skills: Adaptability, Fast-Learner, Problem Solving, Project Management and Leadership

Programming: Python, Java, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, noSQL database (MongoDB), SwiftUI, Amazon Web Services